- 000 请问有什么紧急状况 - 999 请问有什么紧急状况
- Triple-zero, what is your emergency? - 9-9-9, what's your emergency?
911 请问有什么紧急状况
9-1-1, what is your emergency?
没人知道真相到底是什么
No one knows what's true anymore.
这不是世界末日 但看得出…
It's not the end of the world, but you can see…
供电系统全面瘫痪
Power grid has collapsed.
货币变成壁纸
Currency is worthless.
城市付之一炬
Cities are burning.
瘟疫和流行病
Pestilence and pandemics.
灾难性的高温
Catastrophic heat.
我们逐渐耗尽水资源
We're actually running out of water.
你为何要伤害这些人
Why are you hurting these people?
世界局势濒临崩盘
Getting close to the terminal freak-out point.
人类秩序瓦解 开始弱肉强食
Mankind has gone rogue, terrorizing itself.
芙莉欧莎：疯狂麦斯传奇篇章
帮派烧杀掳掠 如蝗虫横扫大地
Gangs are marauding like locusts across the land.
全球土壤酸化
The earth is sour.
- 人类疾病丛生 - 我们经历了半衰期
- Our bones are poisoned. - We have become half-life.
随着世界的瓦解
As the world falls around us,
我们该如何坚强面对残酷的世道
how must we brave its cruelties?
1.难抵极
这颗是我的
This one's for me.
我再摘下那颗给你
I'll get that one for you.
该回去了
We should go back now.
我们跑出来太远了
We've come too far.
芙莉欧莎
Furiosa!
喂 贪心鬼
Hey, Vulture.
小声点
Not so loud.
有见过这么多肉吗
Have you ever seen so much meat?
停下别动
Stay very still.
肉
Meat.
瓦尔基丽 隐身起来 在我回来前都不要乱动
Valkyrie, be invisible. Still as a rock till I get back.
别让人看见你
Be invisible.
小心 小心头
Careful. Careful with the head.
脊椎是我的
That spine's mine.
从那里切下去
Cut right there.
听到了吗
Hear that?
上车 上车
Get on! Get on!
芙莉欧莎 他们掳走了芙莉欧莎
Furiosa! They took Furiosa!
我跟你一起去
I'll come with you.
不行 这里的人更需要你守护
No, they need you here.
知道此处的人都不能留活口
一个也不留
愿星辰与你同在
The stars be with you.
狙击手 有狙击手
Snipers! We got snipers.
只有一个追兵
Lone rider.
她破坏了机车
She fouled us.
被她咬穿了
She bit through it.
喂 你在干嘛
Hey! What are you doing?
给我 给我 给我
Hey, give it. Give it. Give it!
那是雷霆机车
That's the Thunderbike.
That's the Thunderbike!
- 我以为你把车弄烂了 - 我有啊
- I thought you crippled it. - I did!
是谁在追我们
Who's coming for us?
那个人是谁 你老子吗
Who is… who is that? Is that your pa?
那是你爸吗
Is that your father? Who…
喂喂喂
Hey. Hey, hey, hey. Hey!
把女孩丢包吧 他只想要她
Ditch the girl! That's all he wants.
那我们要怎么跟狄门特斯交代
What do we tell Dementus?
我们有马肉
We got horse meat.
这证明不了什么 但有了这女孩 一旦他看到 就会问
It proves nothing. But the girl, once he sees her, he's gonna ask,
「她从哪里来 」 我们就能提供他答案
"Where did she come from?" And we're gonna be the ones to tell him.
再也不会有人看扁我们
No one's gonna scum us anymore.
- 再也不会有人看扁我们 - 再也不会有人看扁我们
No one's gonna scum us anymore!
那个小贱货
That piece of filth!
我们会成功 我们一定会成功
We're gonna make it. We're gonna make it!
我有大消息要给狄门特斯 狄门特斯
I got news for Dementus. Dementus!
脚垢 你带回来什么 独自一个人
What do you got here, Toe Jam? All by yourself.
我只对狄门特斯说
I speak only to Dementus.
不 把手拿开
No. Hands off.
解开她
Untie it.
是我找到的 她是我的
I found it. She's mine.
别碰她
Hands off.
好强壮 真是个小辣椒
It's strong. What a dilly, eh?
- 她是我的 - 你在哪找到的
She's mine. Where did you find it?
- 还给我 - 在哪
- Give it back. - Where?
- 在哪找到的 - 还给我
- Where did you get it? - Give her back.
把她给我 我带她去见他
Give her to me. I'll take her to him.
她来自丰饶之地
She's from a place of abundance.
你在讲什么
What are you talking about?
丰饶之地 那里什么都有
A place of abundance! It's got everything!
在哪
Where?
我只跟狄门特斯谈
I speak only to Dementus.
你来自哪里
Where are you from?
你在哪找到她的
Where did you find her?
我的嘴 狄门特斯的耳朵 我只跟狄门特斯说
My lips, Dementus's ear. My lips. Dementus.
好孩子
Good girl.
原装版JRL牌七福重机
The original JRL Cycles Lucky Seven.
由七缸星形航空引擎驱动
was powered by a seven cylinder radial aircraft engine,
排气量为2800CC
with a swept capacity of 2, 800cc's,
110匹马力 160磅扭力
110 horsepower, 160 pounds of torque.
狄门特斯
Dementus.
狄门特斯 你看我找到了什么
- Dementus. Look what I found.
这位是谁啊
Who do we have here?
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
大家都怎么称呼你
What do they call you?
她来自丰饶之地
She's from a place of abundance.
- 可以看看吗 - 好
- May I? - Mm-hmm.
一个健康 营养良好的全寿人 完美无缺
A healthy, well-nourished full-life. Flawless.
告诉我们你来自哪里 孩子
Tell us where you're from, child. Eh?
告诉你的朋友
Tell your friend.
那里什么都有
It's got everything.
你是怎么知道的
How do you know that?
小比利帮的人告诉我的
A Roobilly told me.
他说是他亲眼所见
He said he saw it with his own eyes.
那他人呢
And where is he?
那我们让脚垢自己来说
Let's hear from Toe Jam.
把他带进来
Bring him in.
你找到她的那个地方 那里很棒 对吗
This place, where you found her, it was amazing, right?
那里什么都有 对吧 有水 有食物 什么都有
It had everything, right? Water, food, everything.
告诉我
Tell me.
他在呛血
He's choking.
让他倒过来好了
Well, hang him upside down.
倒转一下
Downside up.
就是这样
There you go.
画个地图
Draw a map.
画个箭头 画个箭头
Draw an arrow. Draw an arrow!
给我们指路
Show us! Show us!
你也累了一天了 对吧 今天过得很糟
Now, you have had a hard day, haven't you? An awful day.
你肯定累坏了
You must be exhausted.
我只需要你做一件事 那就是好好休息
There's only one thing I need you to do and that is rest.
你什么都不需要告诉我们 一个字都不用说 我保证
You don't have to tell us anything. You don't have to say a word, I promise.
休息就好
Just rest.
明天 我就送你回家
Tomorrow, I'll take you home.
我会跟随你来到这里的踪迹 然后送你回家
I'll follow the tracks that brought you here and I'll take you home.
带她下去 去吃饭和洗澡 用最好的饮用水
Take her, feed her, wash her. Use our best drinking water.
你们两个
You two.
看好她 保护她
Keep an eye on her, keep her safe.
别让那些杂碎接近她
Don't let any of these brutes near her.
喂 你抢了什么
Hey, what you got there?
史奈普 史奈普
Snapper. Snapper!
妈妈
Ma!
饶命 我也有孩子
Please. I'm a mother, too.
我什么都不会说 一个字都不说
I will say nothing, not a word.
拦下她 拦下她
Stop! Stop her!
- 开枪 开枪 - 快开枪
- Shoot! Shoot! Shoot! - Shoot!
不是我的错
It's not my fault.
没事 可以走了
Good, we're good.
你在流血
You're bleeding.
你有听到吗 走 快点
Do you hear that? Come, quick.
他们是怎么追踪我们的
How are they tracking us?
骑到高地 好好躲起来
Ride to high ground. Hide yourself well.
若我一日未归 就自己回家
If I don't find you in one day, go home.
妈妈 我…
Ma, I…
用日月星辰导航
Take your bearings from the sun and stars.
起风时 用风沙掩盖踪迹
When there is wind, use it to cover your tracks.
- 我不愿丢下你 - 芙莉欧莎
- I'm not gonna leave you. - Furiosa!
你是芙佛里尼族人 你要服从命令
You are Vuvalini, you'll do as I ask.
不管要付出什么代价 也无论要花多长时间
Whatever you have to do, however long it takes,
答应我你会找到回家的路
promise me you'll find your way home.
种下这颗种子
Plant this seed.
保护众母绿地
Protect the Green Place.
满足我的心愿 许下承诺
Give me this one gift. Promise.
愿星辰与你同在
The stars be with you.
绕过去 大家绕过去
Go around! Gotta go around!
找别条路绕过去
Find a way around!
妈妈
Ma!
- 告诉我 - 她是你妈 好极了
- Tell me! - She's your mother. Perfect.
你来自哪里
Where are you from?
告诉我
Tell me!
妈妈
Ma!
告诉我们你们来自哪里 我们就放过她
Tell me where you came from and we will cease and desist.
芙莉欧莎
Furiosa!
你只需要用手指出来
All you have to do… All you have to do is just point.
帮我指出正确方向 我就会带你回家
Point me in the right direction and I'll take you home.
不不不 别逃避
No, no, no. Don't look away.
我们不能逃避现实
We mustn't look away.
你有过机会
You had your chance.
史学家 给我们来堂单字课
History Man, a Word Burger, please?
眼泪
Tears.
人类的眼泪
Human tears.
泪腺的分泌物含有油脂
The secretions of the lacrimal gland containing oils,
盐分 蛋白质 和压力荷尔蒙
salts, proteins, and stress hormones.
喜悦和悲伤的泪水 具有不同化学成分
The tears of joy and those of sorrow have different chemical compositions.
是的 所以悲伤的泪水更为…
Yes. Sorrow is more…
辛辣 刺激
…piquant, zesty.
2.来自荒地的课程
为何要逃给我追
Why would you run from me?
现在你手下必须争夺 由谁手刃你的殊荣
Now your followers must fight over who gets to kill you.
我本来会很欢迎 你们每个人的加入
Now, I would've welcomed you. Every one. I woulda brought you in.
你们本可以成为 这个大家庭的一分子
You coulda been a part of this great horde.
现在我们面临难题
Now, we have a problem.
你们有二十个人 却只有五辆机车
There are 20 of you, but only five bikes.
该怎么选
How do we choose?
谁有足够本领 勇气和胆量 来加入狄门特斯的车队
Who's got the goods, the bollocks, the testes to ride with Dementus?
你们得拿出看家本领才行
You're gonna have to show me who you are.
好吗
Yes?
因为今天 我们要仰赖物竞天择
Because today we dance to Darwin.
今天 我们要进行「五车拉拉乐」
Today, we do The Five Bike Teddy.
各就各位 预备 开始
Ready, setty, go!
若你不想看就别看
You don't have to watch if you don't want to.
或许你会想闭上眼
You may wanna close your eyes.
若是你想 这个也可以给你抱
You know, you could hold this if you want.
这是我孩子的玩偶
It belonged to my little ones.
交给你照顾 好吗
Why don't you just keep him safe?
女士和先生们 请启动引擎
Lady and gentlemans, start your engines.
蜥蜴绞肉和人血香肠
Lizard mince and human blood sausage.
你会写字吗
Can you write?
我可以教你 增强你的记忆 你也可以成为史学家
I can teach you. Muscle up your memory. You could become a History Man.
提升你的价值 这样狄门特斯就会照顾你
Make yourself invaluable, and Dementus will look after you.
天文导航
Astronavigation.
透过参考恒星和其他天体的位置
A determination of one's course by reference to the stars.
来决定一个人的路线
and other celestial bodies.
红色信号弹
Red! Red!
要去看看吗 老大
Are we curious, boss?
那我们就去一探究竟吧
Well, let's go have a look.
这里是英灵殿吗
Is this Halvalla?
我来到英灵殿了
Am I in Valhalla?
英灵殿是什么
What's Valhalla?
英灵殿 死者的殿堂 往生英雄的天堂应许地
Valhalla's "The Hall of the Slain." A paradise for dead heroes.
不就好棒棒 我们在找丰饶之地
Good for you. We're looking for a place of abundance.
丰饶是什么意思
What's abundance?
丰富 繁多
Abundance, plentifulness.
意思就是取之不尽 用之不竭
Having a copious quantity of something.
用之不竭是什么
Co… What's "copus quantity"?
意思就是很多 很多好东西
A lotta stuff. A lotta good stuff.
堡垒
The Citadel.
什么垒
The what-a-del?
就是我出生的地方 那里什么都有
It's where I was birthed. It's got everything.
超级多干净活水
A humongous amount of fresh water.
还有绿色的东西
And green stuff.
成堆的作物 蔬菜 还有水
Mountains of pro-juice and veggies and… and water.
要去哪里找这个堡垒
And where would one find this Citadel?
或许是那头
That way maybe.
这又是什么
What are these?
这是天血弹 我用这个招唤了你们
That is sky blood. It called you to me.
快来见证狄门特斯无上的力量
Behold the might of Dementus!
火焰加身的狄门特斯
The Red Dementus.
以及他的毁灭者大军
and his Congress of Destruction.
他前来征服各位
He is here to lay siege on you.
请倾听他的宣言
Listen carefully to his words.
各位
All of you.
所有保护并扶持 这座宏伟堡垒的人民
All who protect and honor this magnificent Citadel,
你们有一个选择
you have a choice.
非常诱人的选择
A very attractive choice.
我想要你们的领导者
I want your leaders.
我想要那些主宰你们的人
I want those who hold dominance over you.
带你们的领导者出列 将他们丢下来
Bring me your leaders and throw them down.
将他们丢下来 就能避免更多的折磨与忧愁
Throw them down, and you'll avoid more suffering and sorrow.
他们剥削你们 他们奴役你们
They exploit you. They enslave you.
他们吸食践踏你们的血汗
They wash their feet in your sweat and blood.
更对你们毫无回馈
and they give you nothing in return.
倾听我们的箴言
Listen to this truth.
大人物能领头 只因你们选择跟随
Big shots rule only because you choose to follow.
权力掌握在你们手中
The power is with you.
你们可以自由选择 到我这边来
You are free to choose. Come to me.
带着你们的痛苦和负担投奔我 我会让每日口粮翻倍
Come to me with your pain and burden, and I will double your grub.
无限量地给所有人提供食物和水
Food and water for everyone, as much you like.
我们会分享所有财富
We will share the wealth.
大家会跟我一起统治灿烂的新荒地
You will rule with me in the splendor of a new Wasteland.
造型真可爱
Adorable.
我好为你担心 小甜心 真的很担心
I'm afraid for you, sweetheart. Really afraid.
因为大吉利会用双手把你扯下来
'Cause Big Jilly here is gonna scoop you out, both ends,
搓碎你的身体 再喂给你吃
mush it up and feed it back to you.
但那完全无法跟诺顿先生
But that ain't nothing compared to what Mr. Norton here.
想要对你做的事相比
is dreaming of doing to you.
因为诺顿先生最恨大人物了
'Cause Mr. Norton really hates big shots.
- 然后还有哈雷先生 - 日安 朋友
- Then there's Mr. Harley. - G'day, mate!
戴维森先生 雷斯戴佩尔
Mr. Davidson, Rizzdale Pell.
还有其他上千名 紧咬你们不放的疯子
and a thousand other mad bastards coming after you,
我完全无法阻止他们
and there ain't nothing I can do to stop 'em.
不死王有个要求
The Immortan has a request.
从他在此集结的所有战士中 选出一人
Among all his warriors assembled here, choose one.
我干嘛要选
Why would I do that?
要想继续进行交涉 你必须随机选出一人
For this negotiation to go further, you must choose at random.
任一位战争男孩 只选一人
Any War Boy. Just one.
若我选择不选呢
What if I choose not to choose?
那你就永远不会知道真相
Then you'll never know the truth.
由我的弄臣来选
My Smeg will choose.
好耶
Yes!
好
Okay.
不 右边那个
Nope. To the right.
荣耀等待着你
You are awaited.
见证我的壮烈成仁
Witness me!
见证吧
Witness!
我们有972位死忠的战士
Among us are 972 devout warriors.
任何一位被选上时 都愿意做出同样牺牲
Any one of them, if chosen, would've done the same.
任何一位都会为不死老乔 名留青史地死去
Each would die historic for the Immortan Joe.
- 所以你们才是傻子 - 你才是傻子
- That's why you're fools. - You're the fool!
只有傻子才会来此挑衅
You're all fools for coming here.
我是史阔塔
I am Scrotus.
而我是瑞塔斯
I am Rictus.
我们是不死老乔之子
We are the sons of the Immortan Joe.
现在我们会杀了你们
And now we're going to kill you.
喂
Hey!
我抓住你了
I gotcha.
当情势不妙时 就得随机应变
When things go bonkers, you have to adapt.
你和我都一样
You, same as me.
他们到了
They're here.
我们很坚强
We're tough.
你这只鲜美的小奶狗
- You're a tender little hound.
满载的武装运输车
A War Rig. Fully loaded.
车队的确来自堡垒 车上还有不死王的印记
It's from the Citadel, all right. It's got the Immortan's mark.
炼油城 荒地第二要塞
用食物和饮用水换取汽油
Food and water for guzzolene.
总比拾荒好
It beats scavenging.
这是我们的天命
This is our destiny.
我们身处机运满满的宝地
We are indeed in the land of opportunity.
看好了
Watch this.
向狄门特斯致敬
All hail Dementus!
狄门特斯
Dementus!
足够所有人使用 几个月分的汽油
Fuel for all, enough for months.
今天真是美好的一天
Thisis truly a great day.
对 但我即将让一切变得更棒
Yeah, well, I'm about to make it a whole lot greater.
你是哪位 把安全帽和外套脱掉
Who are you? Remove your helmet and jacket.
我只听命于八爪老大
I take orders from The Octoboss.
什么
Huh?
好 照他说的做
Yeah, do what he says.
胆敢质疑我的老大权威
Questioning my boss-ority.
好了 这样就行了
All right, that's good.
用这个涂满全身
Cover yourself in this.
就是这样
That's it.
快点 快点
Come on. Come on.
懂吗
Good?
就是这样
There ya go.
选十个手下 毛发越少越好
Choose ten of your men. The balder the better.
死神帮
Mortifiers.
别乱动
Settle down.
有谁想要当战争男孩
Who wants to be a War Boy?
什么事
What?
武装运输车回来了 好像遭受攻击
The rig's coming back. I think they're under attack.
我们要打开大门吗
Do we open the gates?
先不要 情况不太对
No. Something's off.
我得减速
I'm gonna have to slow down.
不 加速 要加速
No. Faster. Go faster.
他们不会打开大门
They won't open the gate.
他们没有中计
They're not buying it.
射杀他们
Shoot them.
什么
What?
我们来玩真的
Make it real.
他说什么
What'd he say?
他想要假戏真做
He wants us to make it real.
你在搞什么
What are you doing?
不 不 不要
No, no. No, no, no!
你是个杂碎 狄门特斯 杂碎
You're scum, Dementus. Scum!
打开大门
Open the gates.
Open the gates!
打开大门
Open the gates.
退下
Back off.
下去
Get off.
把这个交给不死老乔
Give this to Immortan Joe.
接好
Catch.
狄门特斯想要协商
Dementus wants to talk.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
对 让他进来
Yes. Let him come.
先搜身 不准携带武器
Body search, no weapons.
不管他想要什么 我们先听听看
Whatever he wants, we'll listen.
然后再就地诛杀
Then kill him on the spot.
别激动
Calm down.
火焰狄门特斯 赞扬你的生活方式
The Red Dementus commends you on your lifestyle.
也赞扬你同意与我们协商
and for agreeing to these trade negotiations.
若日落前我们没有安全回去 我们就炸毁炼油城
If we're not back safe by sunset, we blow up Gastown.
想要挽救炼油城只有这个方法
This is how you save Gastown.
解除炸弹的六位数密码 只存在于狄门特斯的脑海内
And the six-figure code exists only in the brain of Dementus.
他想要双倍的一切物资
He wants double. Double of everything.
用一个油罐车的清水 来换半个油罐车的汽油
One full tank of water for half a tank of guzzolene.
我们做不到 那是不可能的
Can't do that. Not possible.
那他就只能钢钉穿脑了
Then he gets a spike in the nut.
双倍的母乳 和双倍的水耕作物
Double the mothers' milk and double the hydroponics.
双倍的马铃薯
Double the spuds.
双倍的蛆泥和蟑螂粥
Double the maggot mash and the roach gruel.
我的手下需要多多摄取蛋白质
My boys need all the protein they can get.
求你了 答应他的要求吧
Please. Give him what he wants!
荒地无法维持这种供应量 试算一下就知道
The Wasteland won't sustain it. Run the numbers.
拜托 不死王 我的兄弟
Please, my Immortan. My brother.
快点决定 我要撑不住了
Make up your mind. Can't hold this much longer.
让瑞塔斯解决 老爸
Let Rictus do it, Dad.
我来严刑逼问那组密码
I'll squeeze the code out of him.
来 交给你 交给你
Here, take it. Take it.
你这个智障
Oh, you idiot.
我忘记密码了
I've forgotten the numbers.
等等 等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait.
等等
Wait!
对齁 还在我脑海中 想起来了 想起来了
Yep, it's in there, got it, got it, got it, okay.
肉体的快感差点害我失忆
The pleasure flushed them clean out of my head.
下次别再这么做 兄弟 我脑神经很衰弱的
Don't ever do that again, comrades. I'm a man with a fragile brain.
那个是谁
Who's that?
这位…是我女儿 小狄
That… is my daughter, Little D.
小狄门特斯
Little Dementus.
她看起来跟你一点也不像
She looks nothing like you.
这个嘛 她继承了她完美的母亲
Yes, well, she has her mother's perfections,
完全避开了我的缺陷
and none of my deficiencies.
她妈妈在哪
Where's the mother?
伟大的女人 强悍 聪慧
Magnificent woman. Fierce, intelligent.
却在保护小家伙免受掠夺者侵害时 被残忍杀害了
Taken so cruelly protecting this little one from marauders.
她看起来好苍白
She looks pale.
你看起来才苍白 她很完美
You look pale. She's perfect.
不像你那两个基因突变的怪咖儿子
Not like the genetic absurdities you have for sons.
她很苍白是因为我为了 替他准备血肠而取了一点血
Well, she's pale because I take her blood, for blood pudding that I prepare for him.
你又是谁
And who are you?
我是包治百病的器官维修工
Well, I'm the Organic Mechanic. All things therapeutic.
你千万别搞错 她可是全寿人
Now, make no mistake, she is a full-life.
完全未经人类或疾病的染指
Untouched by man or disease.
你想留在堡垒吗
Would you like to stay here in the Citadel?
若我让你留下 你就能长大成为强壮健康的女人
If I let you stay and you grow to become a strong, healthy woman,
你可以加入我们的后宫
you could become one of our wives.
不行 她是我女儿
No, she's my daughter.
这会像是皇室联姻 能让强强联合
It will be a royal intermarriage. The bonding of dynasties.
我保护了她一辈子
Her whole life I have protected her,
不受风吹日晒和色狼的觊觎
from the sun, the wind, every lecherous gaze.
不行
No.
两强能成为血缘姻亲
You'll be bonded by blood.
不 她是非卖品 她是我的
No! She's not for sale, she's mine.
你怎么说 孩子
What say you, child?
自从她母亲惨死后她就没开过口
She hasn't spoken since her mother's tragic end.
令人心酸
Very poignant.
他是你爸吗
Is he your father?
不是
No.
他残杀了我母亲
He slaughtered my mother.
没错 那是事实
True, that is true.
而我很确信那让她变得更坚强
And I can tell you it made this child tough.
强大到足以克服未来的任何打击
Tough enough to survive all sorrows that may come her way.
我是为了她好才那么做 我是为了她好
I did that for her. I did that for her.
我每趟运货 会多给你三分之一的水量
I will increase your shipment of water. But only by a third.
食物也增量四分之一 但只有马铃薯
I will increase your food by a quarter. Potatoes only.
你们每十天就会收到一批货
You'll get your delivery once every ten days,
但前提是我的武装运输车要安全返回
but only if my War Rigs return safely.
并满载精炼汽油
full of high-grade guzzolene.
成交
Deal.
然后 我要留下这女孩 她不是你女儿
And… I will take this girl, who is not your daughter.
再加上 他
And also, him.
否则 就开战吧
Otherwise, it's war.
只要你乖乖 我就会乖乖
You behave, I'll behave.
我会保护炼油城不受任何侵害
I'll protect Gastown from all treachery.
那里会变得跟堡垒一样坚不可摧
It will be as impenetrable as this Citadel.
在混乱的世道中诞生出稳定局面
Stability born from a world of chaos.
你 我 我们
You. Me. We.
从此以后 请尊称我为「伟大的狄门特斯」
Henceforth, I will be addressed as "The Great Dementus."
重机王国的敬爱领袖
Beloved ruler of Bikerdom.
炼油城的守护领主
Lord Guardian of Gastown.
得快闪了 我可不希望炼油城真的炸了
Gotta go, gotta go. Don't want Gastown to go boom.
多棒的一天 多棒的交易 多棒的一天
What a day. What a deal. What a day.
干得漂亮 老大
Beautifully played, boss.
狄门特斯最高
Peak Dementus!
没事的 你很安全
It's all right. You'll be all right.
好的
All right.
现在快让美丽的小宝宝出来见世界
Now, shove that little beauty out into the world.
来吧 要出来了
Come on. Here it comes.
我能看到头了
I can see its head.
好女孩 好女孩
Good girl. Good girl.
是的 你做得非常好
Oh, yeah. You're very clever.
再用力最后一次
One last shove.
再来一次 再来一次
One more, one more.
很好
Very good.
是男孩吗 是男孩吗
Is it a boy? Is it a boy?
也算是吧
More or less.
抱歉 老大
Sorry, boss.
我会帮你生下全寿人 我知道我能做到
I will give you a full-life! I know that I can.
你已经三振出局了
Three strikes, you're out.
瑞塔斯
Rictus.
拜托 让我留在这里
Please, let me stay.
别担心 亲爱的
Don't fret, love.
你会成为很棒的乳娘
You'll make an excellent milker.
这是什么
What's this?
瑞塔斯 你弄丢什么了吗
Rictus. You lose something?
只是看看 随便看看
Just looking. Just looking around.
在找什么
What for?
没什么
Nothing.
别骗我 你鬼鬼祟祟的 到底想干嘛
No. Don't lie to me. You're up to something.
没什么
- What is it? - Nothing.
那你在这里干嘛
Well, what're you doing here then?
我以为看到有人在跑 好像要逃跑
I thought I saw someone running. Running away.
但那只是我的幻想 惹人心烦的梦
But it was just a dream. An annoying dream.
停
Brake!
司索工 绳索松脱了 去挂好
Dogman. The loose cable! Secure it!
把铲斗救回来 我们需要铲斗
Save the bucket! We need that bucket!
你下去
You go down.
不 换个身材小点的
No. Someone small.
你
You!
快点
Come on.
不 他去
No. Him.
胆子还挺大的 小鬼
You've got a lot of ticker, boy.
司闸员
Brake Man.
你现在晋升为司索工了
You're the new dogman.
3.偷渡者
列队 列队
Line up. Line up.
快快快
Juva-jub-jub.
欢迎来到神圣的造车坊
Welcome to the house of holy motors.
我们要从这个废料场中 利用现有的零件
We're gonna make us something mighty from this boneyard,
打造出强大的新战车
from all these body parts.
两台八缸V型引擎 一个牵引车头的底盘
Two hefty V8 engines, a chassis for a Prime Mover,
2857个寻来的零件
2, 857 found objects.
我们会将它们全部组合
And we are going to put this all together.
并打造出美丽的新战车
We are going to build something beautiful.
我们这样做是为了哪位
And we're doing this for who?
- 不死老乔 - 哪位
- Immortan Joe. - Who?
他会带领我们从末世灰烬中奋起
Who will raise us from the ashes of this world.
你准备好要成为黑手了吗
Are you ready to be Black Thumbs?
不死王
Immorta!
你呢
You?
不死王
Immorta!
那你呢
How about you?
呼喊他的尊号
Speak his name.
他不会说话 他是哑巴
He don't speak. He's mute.
我在哪里看过你
Where have I seen you before?
他是司索工 非常能干
He's a dogman. Very useful.
也太瘦小
Scrawny.
我们还有很多事要做
Oi! We've got work to do.
我们要给自己打造一辆武装运输车
We're going to build ourselves a War Rig.
荒地中最棒的运输神器
The finest piece of grunt in the Wasteland.
更大 更强 更快
Bigger, stronger, faster!
不死王
Immorta!
不死王 不死王 不死王
Immorta! Immorta! Immorta!
我们会在车尾打造防御武器
We are going to build a contraption that will defend the rear.
我们会称之为「流星锤」
We will call it "The Bommyknocker."
那是杰克禁卫官吗
Is that the Praetorian Jack?
他看起来很幸运
He looks lucky.
他是在愤怒道上 载运过最多趟的驾驶
He done the most runs on the Fury Road.
而且每次都成功运回货品
And brung back the booty every time.
喂 杰克禁卫官
Hey. Prae Jack.
你在干嘛
What's going on?
干嘛要不好意思 只不过是小便
Why so shy? It's just piss.
那对疯子兄弟说得没错 它真的很美
They were right, the crazy brothers. She is a mighty thing.
更大 更快 更强 能跑更远
Bigger, faster, stronger, further.
它来了
Here it comes.
看起来像是死神帮
They look like Mortifiers.
死神帮 他们效忠于狄门特斯
Mortifiers. They ride with Dementus.
现在不是了 他们已分家自立
Not anymore. They've gone rogue.
敌袭
Contact.
前方有敌袭
Contact front!
你们 去迎战
You, go!
右边有敌袭 左边有敌袭
Contact right. Contact left.
十字弓 战争男孩
Crossbows, War Boys.
备战
Load up.
在你们身后
Behind you!
现在
快点
Go!
侧翼防御
- 攻击 - 再来一个
更多
活剥他
绕过他们
见证我们的壮烈成仁
Witness!
二号引擎故障
That's engine two.
车顶无人防御 增援
All down on top. Replenish!
我们需要一个短软管和夹钳
We need a short hose and clamps!
短软管 夹钳
Short hose. Clamps.
好耶
Yes!
黑手 黑手
Black Thumb? Black Thumb.
去前面
Up front.
可以启动流星锤了吗
Can I do the Bommyknocker?
- 什么 - 流星锤
- What? - The Bommyknocker.
还不行
Not yet.
注意左边 他们在攻击侧翼
Eyes left. They're flanking us.
注意右边 注意右边
Eyes right. Eyes right.
越来越多追兵了
They're swarming.
黑手
Black Thumb.
黑手 你在吗
Black Thumb! Are you there?
那就抓紧了
Now hang tight.
老杰 老杰
Prae Jack! Prae Jack!
尿童 尿童 水箱故障了
Pissboy. Pissboy! We got a busted radiator.
收到 老杰 现在就去修
Copy P-Jack. On my way.
快喝吧 运输车 喝我的尿
Drink, my rig. Drink this piss.
来啊
Come on.
老杰
Prae Jack.
见证吧
Witness!
不
No!
流星锤 快用流星锤
The Bommyknocker! Do the Bommyknocker!
现在吗
Now?
现在
Now!
靠边停
Pull over.
现在就靠边停 然后下车
You're going to pull over and get out.
停车
Stop!
你以为你要去哪
Where did you think you were going?
若你想逃离堡垒
If you're running away from the Citadel,
相信我 兵工农场比堡垒更恐怖
believe me, the Bullet Farm is a whole lot worse.
剩下的选择只有炼油城 那里由狄门特斯当家做主
The only other place is Gastown. It's in the hands of Dementus.
那个蠢蛋根本无法管控手下
A mug who can't even keep his gangs together.
只有这些地方 没有别处可去了
And that's it. There is nowhere else.
这里是荒地
This is the Wasteland.
不管你以为可以去哪 那里都不存在
Wherever you thought you were going does not exist.
今天很惨烈
It's been a hard day.
我失去了我的车队和组员
I lost my convoy. I lost my crew.
我得从头开始打造一切
I'm gonna have to start again.
我开车离去时心想 我们可以一起重来
And I'm driving off thinking I ought to start with you.
你的视力很好 能随机应变又能保持冷静
You got good vision. You read the play and you keep your head.
你或许还很青涩 但你既强悍又果敢
You may be raw, but you have about you a purposeful savagery.
只要假以时日
You give me time,
我能教会你 公路战争所需要知道的一切
I'll teach you everything you need to know about Road War.
若我们经历一切后你能存活下来
If you survive everything we take on together,
你就会有本事 前往任何你想去的地方
you'll have all the skills you need to get wherever you wanna go.
我不会多问前因后果
No questions asked.
留着吧 你会需要它
Keep it. You'll need it.
4.回家
愿星辰与你同在
The stars be with you.
你和我 小狄
You and me, Little D.
兵工农场 荒地第三要塞
二 四 六 八…
Two… four… six… eight…
好了 运输槽空了
Done. Tank's empty.
所有物资清点完成 包括每一滴母乳
Everything accounted, down to the last drop of Mother's Milk.
- 很好 - 不 才不好
- Good. - No, it's not good.
那个蠢蛋狄门特斯 他快把炼油城整个毁了
That piece of anus-pus, Dementus, is running Gastown into the ground.
还把一切怪罪到别人身上
and blaming everyone but himself.
你告诉不死老乔 我们需要举行会议
You tell Immortan Joe we need a meeting.
一个战争会议
A war meeting.
否则我们很快就会大难临头
Otherwise we're gonna get our tits caught in the wringer.
这是你要的轰鸣枪
Here's the boomstick you asked for.
雷霆长矛和子弹都运上车了
Thundersticks. Bullets all loaded.
给你
For you.
为了之后的旅程
For your travels.
你在这里待够了
You're done here.
可以自由离开
You're free to go.
食物 饮水 和交通工具 不管你需要什么
Food, water, wheels, whatever you need.
我都会帮你准备好
I'll help you put it together.
给我几天时间
Give me a couple of days.
我们护送你们进去
We'll lead you in.
开工 动作快 快点
Move! Hurry up! Come on!
退下 滚远点
Back! Get out then!
退下
Stay back!
退下 往后退
Back! Stand back.
炼油城的乡亲们
Citizens of Gastown.
我和你们一样 都想要吃喝不尽
I want what you want. A full belly…
弹药充足 还要有满缸的汽油
and a fistful of bullets for a tank of gas.
我们得纠正错误
We have to put things right.
今天 我们要付诸行动
And today, we're gonna do something about it.
你是负责人吗
Are you in charge here?
你可以跟我谈
You can speak to me.
好喔
Yeah.
我有消息要传递给不死老乔
Well, I've got a message for Immortan Joe.
这里的情况越来越糟
We're in a black spiral here.
我们无法维持供应量
We can't keep up supply.
大家都说自己被坑了 被偷斤减两了
Everyone is saying they're being swindled and short-changed.
大家都说是我的错 其实这是所有人的错
Everyone is saying it's my fault. It's everyone's fault.
我要跟所有军阀会谈
I want a meeting of the warlords.
我 他 食人兽 和白痴兵工农场
Me, him, the People Eater, that idiot Bullet Farmer.
正午时分在堡垒 时间三天后
High noon at the Citadel. Three days from now.
好
Right.
你们该走了
- Ah, you better go.
没有拿到满载的汽油我们不走
We're not leaving without our tankers full of gas.
现在就走
Go now.
若想安全离开 就跟我来
You wanna get out of here, follow me.
正午时分在堡垒 时间三天后
High noon, the Citadel, three days from now.
别迟到
Be punctual.
你给了他整车的水 两千份母乳
You give him a full tank of water, and 2, 000 tits of Mother's Milk.
却空手而归
and then you return empty-handed.
一滴汽油也没有
Not a drop of guzzolene.
他坑了我们 我们被耍了
He filched us. We're being filched.
我们杀了他 现在就杀
Let's kill him. Right now.
很早以前就该下手的 老爸 早就应该干掉他
Shoulda done it long ago, Dad. Shoulda crushed him, Dad!
父亲 请把武装运输车给我
Father, give me the War Rig.
载满我们所有的火力
Load it up with all of the firepower you've got,
我会将他从地球表面炸飞
and I will blow him from the face of the earth.
我们要如何在他 炸毁炼油城之前下手
How do we do that before he blows up Gastown?
我们可以重建那里
We'll build it again.
那要花上好几世代 蠢材
That'd take generations, you moron.
我们可以重建 就是因为你畏首畏尾他才能白嫖我们
We will build it again. Your way of thinking is how he rooks us.
他用他的疯狂吓退了你
He's got you scared of his crazy.
我们要这么做
Here's what we do!
我们要节约每一滴石油
We conserve every drop of guzzolene,
停驶所有车辆 关闭所有发动机
turn off all vehicles, all generators.
关闭每个水泵 包括四大含水层虹吸抽水器
Turn off every water pump including the Big Four Aquifer Siphons.
快去
Get.
天一亮 就开着 空的运输车前往兵工农场
At first light, leave for Bullet Farm with your tankers empty.
然后尽可能多载点弹药回来
Then, return with every munition you can load.
我要每种子弹和枪械 每个口径和尺寸
I want every bullet and firearm, every caliber and size.
你的整个步兵队伍都要准备好作战
Your entire infantry ready to pick up.
很好
Good.
过来瞭望台 我们现在就向他们发出讯号
Come to the watchtower. We'll signal them now.
谢天谢地 我们终于要攻击炼油城了
Hell and Hall-elujah! We're gonna take Gastown.
攻击他 趁他最没防备时攻击他
Hit him! Hit him when he least suspects it.
我们要如何阻止他引爆炼油城
How do we stop him blowing up Gastown?
位于你秘密地图终点处的地方
This place at the end of your map of secrets.
那在哪里
Where is it?
我的父母原本是军人
My mother and father were soldiers.
就连世界末日时 他们仍渴望为正义而战
Even as the world fell, they yearned to be warriors for a virtuous cause.
但他们没能做到
For them, it never happened.
我想帮你找到那地方
I wanna help you find this place.
不管那在哪里
Wherever it may be.
跟我走
Come with me.
准备好了吗
Ready?
我想要你的重机
I want your bikes.
把它们绑在追击冲锋车的后面
Load them on the back of the V8 Pursuit and tie them down.
等绑好后
Soon as that's done,
再装上食物 汽油 和水
load it with food, fuel and water.
能载多少载多少
As much as you can carry.
这是要干嘛 去当侦察先锋吗
What's this? A scouting party?
或许吧
Possibly.
那我们呢
What about us?
你们就坐在油罐车上
You're both gonna ride on the tanker.
那我呢
What about me?
你被升职了 担任后方防守
You're promoted. Rear defense.
- 在武装运输车上 - 当然
- On the War Rig? - Of course.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
有问题吗
Is there a problem?
你来开冲锋车
You drive the V8.
我要开武装运输车
I drive the War Rig.
今天不行 今天你开冲锋车
Not today. Today you drive Pursuit.
- 那我要干嘛 - 你跟着我
- What am I gonna do? - You're with me.
- 坐前面吗 - 坐前面
- Up front? - Up front.
等我们载好武器弹药后 你就把运输车开回去
As soon as we load up the weapons and munitions, you can drive the rig back.
直接回家吗 回堡垒
All the way home? To the Citadel?
对
Yep.
上吧
Go on.
想见识一下这辆车的威力吗
Wanna see what this can do?
启动第二引擎
Hit the second engine.
全死了吗
All dead?
不确定
Don't know.
狙击手伏击
Sniper ambush!
他有援军 在外面
He's got backup. Outside.
在两截油罐车间
Between the tanks.
我看不到他
I can't see him.
小心后面
Behind you.
别失手
Do not miss.
他们在哪 能看到吗
Where are they? Can you see them?
在墙脊上 大门左边
On the ridge, to the left of the gate.
给我
Give me that.
好了 帮我填充 快点
All right, load me up. Come on.
过来
Come here.
杰克
Jack!
好了吗 我们走
Yeah? We're good.
我们朝东开三日
We'll head east for three days.
一旦越过悬崖和盐滩平原后
Once we clear the escarpment and the great salt plains,
就改骑重机横越沙丘 一路直下
we'll take the bikes over the dunes all the way.
一路直下
All the way.
怪手 我们用怪手
The digger. Let's use the digger.
没时间了
No time.
下车
Out.
冲啊 冲啊
Fang it! Fang it!
喂
Hello?
这个还活着
This one's still alive!
很好
Good.
过来这里
Get up here.
快点 过来这里
Come on, get up here.
你们有看到吗
Did you see that?
看到他们如何为彼此奋战 像一对小战友
You see how they fought for each other, this little army of two?
他们如此满怀希望地是想奔向哪里
Where were they going, so full of hope?
根本没有希望
There is no hope!
他们没有 你们没有 我当然更没有
Not for them, not for you! Certainly not for me!
我攻下兵工农场那天 这两人来搅局
The day I acquire Bullet Farm, these two destroy it.
我主宰炼油城 我攻下兵工农场 借此 我可以逼降堡垒
I had Gastown, I had Bullet Farm. With that, I coulda crippled the Citadel.
- 杰克 - 并统治荒地
- Jack. - Ruled the Wasteland!
- 我本可以让荒地 - 我的杰克
- The Wasteland woulda been… - My Jack.
- 变成更好的地方 - 芙莉
- …a far better place for all of us. - Fury.
- 杰克 - 不行
- Jack. - No!
起来
Get up.
你们两个 真的很伤我的心
You two. You two break my heart.
你们让我心碎 那不公平
You break my heart. And that's not fair.
你们让我成为黑暗的狄门特斯
You make me the Dark Dementus.
而黑暗的狄门特斯 绝不能容许自己心软
The Dark Dementus cannot afford to be soft!
这是我身为领袖必须付出的代价
It's the price I pay to be your leader!
这是我们在荒地求生存 都必须付出的代价
It's the price we all pay to survive in the Wasteland.
我们不能心软
We cannot be soft!
我们有仇一定要报
There must be retribution.
主持公道和有仇必报
Justice and retribution.
喂 喂
Hey, hey, hey!
我要让她先看着 把她吊起来
I want her to watch a while. String her up.
你跟着去吧 跟着去吧 跟着去吧
You're going. You're going. You're going.
走啰
Let's go.
兄弟 用受伤的那只手
No, mate, other arm.
怎么 你越来越生疏了
What? You lost your touch?
我来
I'll do it.
来啊 小猪仔 起来 起来
Come on, piggy! Get up. Get up!
出去吧 快去
Let's go. Go.
弄臣
Smeg!
够了 够了
Enough! Enough!
我腻了
I'm bored.
休闲时间结束 我们回家
Let's end our cares and go home!
没事的
It's all right.
继续睡吧 我会让你舒服点的
Go back to sleep. I'll make it nice for you.
留下来
Stay!
你在这里至少可以安祥地死去
You'll find peace here.
我是芙莉欧莎禁卫官
I'm the Praetorian Furiosa.
I am the Praetorian Furiosa!
你发生什么事
What happened to you?
拉上去
Pull.
有看到他的踪迹吗
Any sign of him?
没有
No.
但在炼油城有不寻常的动静
But there's something going on at Gastown.
我想他要炸毁炼油城了
I think he's blowing up Gastown.
胡说
Rubbish.
你自己看
- Take a look.
他先是缺席会议 现在又这样
He fails to turn up to a meeting and now this.
是假的
It's fake.
那样做完全没有任何好处
There's no possible advantage.
我们不该迟疑的
We shouldn't have waited.
我们为何要按兵不动 现在就出发前往炼油城
Why're we waiting now? Let's go to Gastown now.
他不在炼油城
He's not at Gastown.
杰克禁卫官在哪
Where's Praetorian Jack?
我们的武装运输车呢
Where's our War Rig?
他拿下了兵工农场
He's taken the Bullet Farm.
你在说谎
You're lying.
他拿下了兵工农场 接下来就要打来这里了
He's taken the Bullet Farm, and he's coming here next.
你是如何知道的
How do you know that?
他们带着攻墙的家伙来了
They're coming with grappling hooks and ladders.
他想要拿下堡垒
He wants to take the Citadel.
那我们就去兵工农场
Then we go to the Bullet Farm.
现在就跟他正面对决
Meet him head-on right now.
炼油城正在燃烧 他人在炼油城
It's Gastown that's burning. He's at Gastown.
他想要把你们骗去炼油城
He wants to draw you to Gastown.
让堡垒人去楼空 无人防守
He wants you to leave the Citadel exposed.
那我们就留在这里
So we stay here.
我们有三个选择：懦夫的选择
We have three choices. The coward's choice.
留在这里 并让狄门特斯扰乱我们的心智
Stay here and let Dementus mess with our minds.
傻瓜的选择 在前往兵工农场的路上
The fool's choice, go out and meet an invisible enemy.
与一支隐形军队作战
on the road to the Bullet Farm.
又或是战士的选择 前往炼油城歼灭他们
Or the warrior's choice, go to Gastown and crush him.
选择权在我 误导他去以为我们要去炼油城
It is my choice. We make him think we're going to Gastown.
若你抓到他 他的命是我的
If you find him, he's mine.
有了 有了
Yes. Yes!
他们确定朝炼油城出发了
They're Gastown bound for sure.
真好骗
So gullible.
我深深地鄙视他们
I hold them profoundly in contempt.
各位 时候到了 战争时刻到来
Gentlemans, it's time. Time to do war.
是时候夺回本就属于我们的东西
Time to take back what's rightfully ours.
朝堡垒前进
To the Citadel.
派对开始
Let's party!
这世上永远都会有战争开打
There always was, is, and will be war.
苏美人曾与埃兰人作战
The Sumerian fought the Elamite.
撒克逊人也曾与维京人作战
The Saxon fought the Viking.
历史总在不断地复制上演
And so the histories grew.
曾有玫瑰战争 橘子战争
There were the Wars of the Roses, The Oranges.
鸦片战争
The Opium Wars.
一日战争 六日战争 千日战争
The One-Day, Six-Day, Thousand-Day Wars.
南北对抗 东西相争
North against South. East against West.
第一 第二 第三次 无数次关于宗教和正义的战争
The first, second, third countless wars of religion and righteous belief.
石油战争 水源战争 三国核战
The Oil Wars. Water Wars. The Tri-Nation Nuclear War.
新兴城镇之战
The Battle of the Boomtowns.
而现在 亲爱的 四十天荒地战争
And now, my dears…The Forty-Day Wasteland War.
以眼还眼
Eyes for eyes.
以牙还牙
Teeth for teeth.
悲伤让怒火燎原
Rage fueled by grief.
我需要交通工具
I need a vehicle.
这里什么都没有 连重机都没有
There's nothing here, not even a bike.
- 把我降下去 - 你要怎么做 用走的吗
Winch me down. - What're you gonna do? Walk?
我有一台车
I've got a vehicle.
我等不及要给你看了
Can't wait for you to see it.
她是不是很美
Isn't she wonderful?
喂 你们瞧
Hey! Look at this.
这个尺寸应该符合
I think this one might fit.
装装看 装装看
Try it on! Try it on!
我们每浪费一秒 那个杂种就会逃得更远
Every moment wasted, that mongrel gets farther and farther away.
要出来了
Coming up!
还要把旧车上的油抽走
And I want her fuel too.
把油和水抽干 所有武器拆走
I want all of her fuel, and her water and her weapon.
那个傻蛋可以逃 但他躲不了多久
A fool can run, but he can't hide.
尺寸肯定相符
It's gonna fit.
喂 史阔塔
Hey, Scrotus.
- 史阔塔 - 干嘛
- Scrotus! - What?
你需要先好好吃一餐 来点狗肉串
You'll need some proper tucker. Canine kebab.
我们打包带走
We'll take it with us.
你的「我们」是什么意思
What do you mean, "us?"
我要跟你一起去
I'm coming with you.
不 你不行去 你只会拖累我
No, you're not. You'll slow me down.
我要确保那蠢蛋狄门特斯这次死透
I'm gonna make sure that dumb Dementus is dead.
不 不行 你留下来吃狗肉串
No, you're not! You stay here and eat some dog.
那是什么
What was that?
那是暗黑天使
That is the darkest of angels.
启示录中的第五骑士
The fifth Rider of the Apocalypse.
5.超越复仇
都是些什么人
Who are they?
能力超强且满怀怨恨的人
Someone competent and excessively resentful.
他们想要什么
Who do you suppose they want?
远离手下并落单的我
Me, without my crew.
我们在这里埋伏 突袭他
We'll wait here. Ambush him.
我们回去
Let's go back.
不不 我们得分散开来
No, no, no. We have to split up.
就这样 没时间拥抱告别了
Here, no time for long goodbyes.
我们一起干了不少大事
We've done some mighty things together.
掰了
Goodbye.
我不是狄门特斯
I'm not Dementus!
我们交换了重机
We swapped bikes!
你找到我了
You've found me.
怪胎
Freakish.
你就是个怪胎
You are a freak.
你可以在半夜割喉让我速死 但你没有
You could have necked me in the night, but you didn't.
所以你肯定是另一种人
So, you must be that other thing.
你是那种人吗
Are you that thing?
我什么也没有
I have nothing.
什么也不是
I am nothing.
任凭你处置
I'm yours.
记得我吗
Remember me?
你这完美的造物
You fabulous thing.
你从比地狱还深的无情坟墓中爬出
You crawled out of a pitiless grave, deeper than Hell.
只有一样东西能促使你向前
And only one thing's gonna do that for you.
那不是希望 而是恨
And not hope. Hate.
满心仇恨也没关系 那是世上最强大的力量之一
No shame in hate. It's one of the great forces of nature.
那不是心存希望 只是本能
That wasn't hope, that was instinct.
所以…
So…
今天就是我的死期
…this is the day I die.
之前总是好奇我会怎么…
I've always wondered how…
十五年前有个女人
Fifteen years ago there was a woman.
唉呦 原来还有隐情
Oh, so there's more to this.
你记得她吗
Do you remember her?
能给我点提示吗
Do I get a clue?
好喔 没问题
Right, okay. Um…
红发 连阴毛都是红的
Redhead. Even her pu…
她是你妈 你姐
Was she your mother? Sister?
她有求饶吗 有尖叫吗
Did she beg, did she scream?
我记得的通常都是最少求饶的
The ones who yell the least tend to stick in my mind.
尽管你对她万般折磨 她还是强大不屈
Despite everything you did to her, she was magnificent.
原来你也在场
Oh, you were there.
我的童年 我的母亲
My childhood. My mother.
我要你还给我
I want them back.
你当然会那么想
Of course you do.
我要你还给我
I want them back!
我以前也有同样的痛
That's exactly how I felt.
我自己的家庭 我美丽的家人
My own family. My own magnificent beauties.
同样被如此不公地剥夺了
Taken so unjustly. Immutably.
我跟你一样 我跟你同病相怜
I'm right there, I'm right there with you.
我也一心渴望复仇
I too craved nothing but revenge.
满心都只想复仇血恨
A big bellyful of revenge.
我想建议…
If I may…
若从背后开枪
If the shooter goes around the back,
受刑人就不会知道子弹何时击发
the shootee won't know the precise moment of the execution.
只是小小的折磨 但毕竟有一点算一点
Minor torture, but every little bit counts.
无论如何 那把猎鼠枪 会快速将我脑浆变成粉色水雾
Either way, that rat shot will turn my brain into a pink mist so fast,
我甚至不会听到枪声
I won't even hear the sound of the gun.
我会听到
I'll hear it.
- 我终其一生都会听到 - 你当然会
- I'll hear it for the rest of my days. - Of course you will.
- 我的手还会感受到后座力 - 当然
- I'll feel the kickback in my hand. - Sure.
我会记得你的脸
I'll remember your face.
当子弹穿透你大脑的软组织时
As the slug worms its way into the soft matter of your brain,
会带走那些被你称为逻辑的想法
taking with it what you call your reason.
还有你的记忆
And your memory,
幸好关于我母亲的记忆 会从中缺席
from which my mother will fortunately be absent.
太高明了
Brilliant.
我会死掉 而你还是会继续哀吊
I'll be dead and you'll still be sorrowing.
你那可爱又强大的好妈妈
your lovey-dovey and your mommy magnificent.
你这个蠢蛋
You idiot.
你永远无法弥补他们所承受的苦
You can never balance the scales of their suffering.
- 还给我 - 我做不到
- Give them back. - I can't!
亲爱的 你想要的是看我痛哭流涕
What you want, dear, are my cries of anguish.
挖心掏肺的痛苦
Anguish without end.
若我能让你满意 我很愿意
And if I could give you that, I would.
但我无惧于错失天堂路
But I don't fear the loss of bliss in Heaven.
也不害怕地狱来索命
Or retribution in Hell.
而且我对疼痛的耐受度 更是出奇的高
And I've got a fiendishly high pain threshold.
来 再来一次
Again, do it again.
若你不让我好死 那就慢慢地折磨我吧
If you can't do me quick, you'll have to do me slow.
但你永远不可能借此获得心灵的平静
But you are never going to get anything close to what you want.
小狄
Little D?
我一直在等你
I have been waiting for you.
我一直在等待像你这样的人 一个配得上我的人
I've been waiting for someone like you, someone worthy of me.
没有荣誉感 更无视法理秩序
No honor, no rule of law to sort things out.
只是荒地中的两个邪恶混帐
Just two evil bastards out here in the Wasteland.
你杀了我 只要下手得宜 你就能成为我
You do this, you do this right, you become me.
- 我跟你一点也不像 - 你就是我
- I am nothing like you. - You are me.
一个活死人
Already dead.
为了感觉活着 我们寻求感官刺激
To feel alive, we seek sensation.
任何刺激 只为了掩盖住躁郁的邪恶悲伤
Any sensation to wash away the cranky black sorrow.
但我们只能短暂遗忘 但悲伤很快就会返回
And it leaves us for a moment, but then it comes back,
我们只好一再重复
and we have to do it all again.
很快我们就需要更多刺激
And we need more,
每次都需要更多 直到再怎么也不够
and each time we need more until too much is never enough.
我们已是活死人 小狄
We are the already dead, Little D.
你和我
You and me.
问题是…
The question is…
你有强悍到 足以精彩地干掉我吗
…do you have it in you to make it epic?
她先是让他永远无法说话 最后的时光里两人沉默以对
She took away his voice, and they spent the rest of the day in silence.
有些人会希望 她不仅只是单纯地射杀他
There are those who prefer that she did more than shoot him.
他们声称 她以更合适的方式了结了他
They claim that she ended him in ways more fitting.
他们讲述着正义的变态 和诙谐的刑罚
They tell of righteous perversities and witty mutilations.
但以下才是芙莉欧莎 亲口对我诉说的真相
But this is the truth whispered to me by Furiosa herself.
在堡垒深处 地处高地的水耕花园里
Deep in the Citadel, high up in the hydroponic gardens,
有棵不同寻常的树
there is a tree unlike any other.
由人体为土壤 更吸食其养分
Its soil is human. Its nutrients human.
蛆虫蚕食他衰败的肉体
Maggots debriding his necrotic flesh.
那是一个从生命体中 孕育出的绿色生机
It was an echo growing out of a living being.
这是我们的第一颗果实 但这不属于你和我
This is our first fruit, but it's not for you and me.
你我终有一日会从这世上消失
Each of us in our own way will vanish from this Earth.
然后或许…
And then perhaps…
某些未经污染过的生命 能再度降临 为这世界增添色彩
…some uncorrupted life will rise to adorn it.
翻译：张君怡